Hello friends, welcome to Health Advisor
channel. By looking at the thumbnail, you must have guessed what
I will tell you in this video.
We will talk about both the new and old variants of Star Health Insurance. We will discuss the
difference between the two and the
new features that have been added. We will know this in
detail. So watch the video till the end so that
you do not miss any important update. And
yes, if you have not yet subscribed to my channel, then
please
subscribe and do not forget to press the bell icon so
that you keep getting the best videos.
First of all, if we talk about these changes, then the first thing that
comes first is the coverage amount. Earlier, this
policy of yours, Star Health Comprehensive, was
available from ₹ 5 lakh to ₹ 1 lakh, but now the company
is ready to give you coverage from ₹ 1 lakh to ₹ 1 crore. PED means
Pre-Extended Disease.
Earlier, your comprehensive plan had a
coverage period of 4 years. For your
ailment,
extra money will be given for your ailment, equal to sum shot.
This option was available in the free of cost comprehensive plan earlier also.  But the
condition was that
you will
not get extra money for the same disease on which you have already spent money. But now
after the new update, the company says that
we are ready to give you extra money even for the same disease.
Buy back of PD is a new
addition in the plan. Earlier, whatever
pre-existing disease you had, the company used to
cover it. After 4 years, now the
company has reduced it to 3 years.
But you have been given an option that if
you want, you can
reduce this waiting period to 1 year by paying extra premium.
Health checkup: Earlier, you used to
get a complete body health checkup in the comprehensive plan after 3 years of continuous claim free coverage. Now the company will give you Rs. 1000 every
year. Earlier you used to get Rs. 5000 in the 5 lakh variant,
now you will get Rs. 1000. It has reduced, yes the
amount has reduced, but now you will get it every year.
Earlier you used to get Rs. 7500 in the 75 lakh and 10 lakh variants,
now you will get Rs. 1000 in the 75 lakh policy.
000 in the ₹00 and 10 lakh variants.
Earlier you used to get 000 in the ₹15 lakh, 20 lakh and 25 lakh variants. Now
you will get 000 in the ₹15 lakh variant. Whereas in the ₹20 lakh
and 25 lakh variants you will get
5500. In the ₹50 lakh, 75 lakh and 1 crore coverage,
you will get health checkup up to 000.
Talking about the cost of ambulance,
earlier the
company used to give you ambulance charges as per your coverage, but now the
company is ready to give you the actual expenses.
Whatever the cost, the company will
provide you AYUSH treatment. The
company is also ready to give you money for Ayurvedic, Unani, Siddha and Homeopathic treatment.
Earlier this was not in your policy. The
money you will get for AYUSH treatment will be
given as per your coverage.
If your coverage is from ₹5 lakh to ₹1 lakh, then the
company is ready to give you 000. Whereas
if you have a variant of ₹20 lakh or 25 lakh, then the
company will give 0000.  If you have a variant of Rs 50 lakh, 75 lakh or 1
crore, then the
company is ready to give you up to Rs 0,000 for alternate medicines.
Pre and
post hospitalization which you used to get for
30 and 60 days, now the company has increased it to
60 and 90 days. Air
ambulance: Earlier, you used to get this benefit
only on Rs 10 off sum inshot and
this option was not available in the Rs 5 lakh variant,
but now you will get this benefit in every variant from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 1 crore
and the
limit kept by the company is Rs 1 lakh per event. The maximum amount that the company is ready to
give you is Rs 1 lakh. Hospital cash for air ambulance: The
company
is ready to give you some money on a daily basis. If you are
hospitalized, the amount you will get
depends on your coverage.
If you have a coverage of Rs 1 lakh, then the
company will
give you coverage in Rs 5000000 and Rs 10 lakh variants.
If the variants of Rs. 50 per day, Rs. 15 lakh and Rs. 20 lakh are
available with you, then you will get Rs. 1 per
day as hospital cash. On Rs. 25 lakh,
you will get Rs. 1500000. If the
policy is of Rs. 75 lakh or Rs. 1 crore, then the company used to give you Rs. 2500000. It is still 2 years old, but yes, the company has now decided to give more money than before. In the policy of Rs. 5 lakh, the
company used to give you Rs. 10000 for normal delivery and Rs. 10000
if your baby was born through C-section,
but now the company has increased the limit.
In normal delivery, you are giving Rs. 10000
and if your baby is born through C-section, i.e. operation, then the
company is
ready to give you expenses up to Rs. 100000.
In the variant of Rs. 75 lakh, earlier you used to get Rs. 100000 for normal delivery,
now you will get Rs. 2500000 for
C-section. Earlier you used to get Rs. 100000, but the
company has kept it the same.  Right now it is giving only ₹40,
whereas in the variants of 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh and
25 lakh, where earlier you used to get
₹2500000 in normal delivery,
now you will get ₹1000000 for normal delivery
and if the baby is born through C section i.e. operation,
then you will get up to ₹5000000, ₹50 lakh,
75 lakh and ₹1 crore in normal delivery,
you will get ₹5000000 and if the
baby is born through C section, then the company will give expenses up to ₹1 lakh.
Newborn baby cover is
₹5000000 in the variant of 5 lakh and in the other higher
variants i.e. in the variants of 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20
lakh or 25 lakh, earlier you used to get up to ₹1 lakh,
now in the variants from 5 lakh to 25 lakh,
you will get ₹1 lakh and
variants of 50 lakh, 75 lakh and 1 crore  ₹ 1 lakh
vaccination Earlier, you used to
get ₹ 000 for vaccination in all the variants but
now the company has changed it and made it ₹ 5
and 7 lakh variants Rs. 000, ₹ 10 lakh, 15
lakh, 20 lakh and 25 lakh variants Rs. 0000
and ₹ 50 lakh, 75 lakh and 1 crore variants Rs.
000 OPD means out patient department
means such expenses for which you are
not admitted 24 hours like your doctor's
fees, medicines, X-ray, blood test,
ultrasound, CT scan, so the company is ready to
give you money for such expenses also in
which eye and dental is also covered,
you get this feature in Star Comprehensive
Plan once in 3 years that is once every
year in 5 lakh and 7 lakh variants,
you will get ₹ 000 in both the new and old plans,
similarly in the variants from 10 lakh to 25 lakh,
you will get ₹ 0000, this is
kept the same, the company has given ₹ 50 lakh for both the new and old
variants  In the policy of 75 lakh and 1
crore, you will get ₹5000000. Let us
know the consultation concept in
brief. If there is a variant of old sum insured i.e. ₹55 lakh to
₹2500000, then the
company has kept the amount same. For your OPD (
Other Than Eye and Dental) you will get ₹5 lakh on
₹2000000 variant,
₹10 lakh on ₹15 lakh, ₹2000000
in ₹20000000 variant,
₹3300 in 25 lakh variant. In the new sum insured of 50 lakh, 75 lakh and 1
crore,
you will get ₹5000 maximum. Now let us talk about
two unique features which are not available with any other company. The
first one is
accidental death coverage which will be
equal to your actual sum insured. Accidental death coverage
Or if you suffer partial or total
disability, in that case the
company is ready to give your nominee the entire lump sum amount
equal to your coverage. For
clinical surgery, that is, if you want to lose weight through surgery to reduce your obesity, then the
company is ready to cover that too,
but for this feature
you will have to wait for at least 3 years.
After 3 years the company covers it and the amount it is
giving you is 22.5 lakhs, in
which you can spend up to ₹ lakhs by including pre and post
waiting
periods. You will be covered from the first day of
accident after 30 days. Any fresh
illness, be it critical or seasonal chronic disease
like stone, cataract, piles, etc., the
company will cover you after 2 years.
Otherwise, if you have any issue before taking the policy,
such as BP, asthma,
diabetes, hypertension, thyroid, cholesterol
or any other, then in that case the company will cover you.
After 3 years, the exclusions will remain the same as before.
are always common Drink and drive
Suicide attempt Cosmetic surgeries Weight loss
therapy HIV AIDS and by birth illness
If you liked this video then please
like it, comment and share it with your friends
Yes if you have
not subscribed to my channel yet then please
subscribe and don't forget to press the bell icon
so that you keep getting the best videos
first
[Music]